

# Dereje Seifu ◆ Addis Abeba, Ethiopia → +251966016473 Fullstack Developer and UI / UX designer 1 year of experience Derejeseifu3030@gmail.com

drjseifu1991 🕠 drjseifu1991 🛅 derejeseifu Bē

Pursuing a position as a Full-stack developer. And I have freelancing experience building websites and designing UX/UI for a network of devoted clients, and I have a passion for developing engaging user experiences. I've worked with Javascript, React, Express, NodeJs, and VueJs.

Skills: React NodeJs ExpressJs Javascript Database Design VueJs SQL, MySql, MongoDbHTML/CSS/Bootstrap UX/UI Design Git/Github/GitLab **Product Design** Figma / Adobe XD / Adobe Photoshop / Adobe Illustrator Team Wok **Problem Solving** Time Management

#### Experience

Rensys Engineering

Sep 2022 to Present

Fullstack Developer and UX/UI Designer Addis Abeba

I am working at Rensys Engineering for a 3-month contractual Fullstack Developer and UI/UX Designer. And I am participating in a project called Coldroom Management System.

Freelance Ethiopia

Mar 2021 to Present

Web Design and Development Freelancer

Since 2021 I was doing web design and development freelancing work with my team. Some of the projects we have done are College Management System for Horizon College and Digital Marketing, and Sales Management System for Rensys Engineering.

Intern as Software Engineer ada.org.et

Apr 2021 to Aug 2021

Amhara Development Association Bahir Dar, Ethiopia

I spent four months working as an Intern Software Engineer at Amhara Development Association, where I helped the team of developers create a Balanced Scorecard system (BSC).

#### Education

Bahir Dar University bdu.edu.et

Oct 2018 to Aug 2022

Bachelor's of science, Software Engineering

CGPA 3.72

BiT Business Incubation and Techno Entrepreneurship Center

Apr 2022 to May 2022

Human Centerd Design

### Projects

#### Super Woman UX UI Design

www.behance.net/gallery/147683937/Super-Woman-Web-and-Mobile-App-UX-UI-Case-Study

Superwomen Ethiopia is a mobile and web-based social media platform that aims to empower the next generation of Ethiopian girls by giving them access to trustworthy information, motivating experiences, and positive role models.

#### **Digital Marketing and Sales Application**

github.com/drjseifu1991/Digital-Sales-and-Marketing-Application

Digital Marketing and Sales Application is a web and mobile based e-commerce platform developed for Rensys Engineering and Trading PLC.

HTML, Laravel, CSS, Vue, JavaScript

#### Covid-19-Informative-App

twitter.com/DYenesew/status/1243828173785137154 g github.com/drjseifu1991/Covid-19-Informative-App

The Covid-19 Infomative App is an Android mobile application that will help to create awareness of Covid-19.

Java, Firebase

#### Fake-news-detector-AI-project

github.com/drjseifu1991/Fake-news-detector-Al-project

A web application for detecting fake news from real ones utilizing Natural Language Processing.

Python, Jupyter Notebook, Flask

#### Horizon College Student Information Management

github.com/drjseifu1991/horizon\_college\_sims

Horizon College Student Information Management is a web application developed for Horizon College to manage student information.

CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Vue, Laravel

Languages –			
Amharic Fluent En	nglish Excellent Afaan Oromo	Fluent	

#### References

## Biniam Behailu (Lecturer | Software Developer | Graphics Designer | Research Group Leader) biniambehailu3@gmail.com

It is my pleasure to write a recommendation for Mr. Dereje Seifu. We first met when I was his mentor and examiner on a project.

During our time together, Dereje displayed great talents in software development, UI/UX design, and several other programming languages & tools. When we first met, I was immediately impressed with his technical skills. It's not just his technical skills that impressed me, his positive attitude and eagerness to stick tightly to his work are something that I personally admire.

I am absolutely confident that Dereje would be a great fit for IT-related businesses, especially in software development. Not only will he bring the kind of skills and experience you are looking for as a professional, but, he will also quickly become an asset and help you grow in any way he can.